So, I've been experimenting with AI
models editing videos for me for a long
time. Super powerful models like Fable
5.1 and GBD6 Astra, but OBUS 5.5 is
giving me some of the best outputs ever.
Take a look at this example, which was
just one prompt.
Not only does this thing do the motion
design and the sound design, but it also
will go out and it will grab the B-roll
and it will grab screenshots or even
generate images and videos for you if it
needs it. It has amazing taste and it
does good with verification. So, today
I'm just going to talk about how you
actually get this set up because all you
have to do is use your natural language.
And yes, of course, that entire intro
that you just watched was edited with
Opus 5.5. This is the actual video. As
you can see, all of these motion
graphics that it did were created right
inside of here inside of Claude. And
what's cool about this is I specified a
lot of things that I wanted, but it got
really creative here. And that's one of
the things about Opus 5.5 is that it has
amazing amazing taste. So, let me show
you what I actually said in this prompt.
So, I gave it the original video and I
said that I need you to edit this to be
super engaging and clean with
hyperframes, which is the actual tool
that we're using here. It's completely
free and we give Claude Code this tool
and it basically writes HTML and
animates it. So if you need to get set
up with hyperframes, then just go to
Google, type hyperframes. You can go to
the website here, but ultimately you're
just going to want to go to this GitHub
repo for hyperframes. And then you just
need to literally copy this link, the
URL, give it to Cloud Code, and say,
"Hey, set up Hyperframe so that we can
use it to animate videos." That's it.
And then on top of that, I have this
free repo called Hyperframe Student Kit.
And in here, it has all of the skills
and examples that I actually have done
with my pipeline of editing videos. And
if you want to get this, you can go to
my free school community. The link for
that is down in the description. In here
you go to classroom and you can click on
all YouTube resources or you can go to
AI skills and you can access that
hyperframes student kit. Anyways, I said
the first step is for you to transcribe
the video so you can make sure that
motion graphics and animations come in
at the exact perfect time. So it has to
transcribe the video. You can do that
using something like 11 Labs API or you
can do that with something like Whisper
which is more of a local model that can
run and transcribe videos but 11 Labs is
a little bit quicker. So 11 Labs you pay
per usage and Whisper is going to be
free but it's just a little slower. So
you can use either one and it's really
simple to get that set up. You just ask
cloud code go to help you set that up. I
said then you will build the animations
based on my instructions. When I say
powerful models like Fable 5.1 and GBD6
Astra, I want you to have animations
come in where I'm pointing. So that was
basically right here where I point and I
have Fable 5.1 come in right over here.
And then I have GBD6 Astra come over
here. And I told it that I wanted to
have a claw logo and I wanted to have an
open eye logo. I wanted it to be
animated. That's basically all I said
besides also saying make sure there's
some sort of liquid glass card behind
the element as it's animated. Otherwise,
it will be hard to see. And as you saw
right here, we got liquid glass right
behind it so that we could actually read
the text and see the logo. So that was
me using natural language as you see.
Then I said, when I say best outputs
ever, I want you to have all three of
those words at the bottom and highlight
them. And so that's what it did right
down here. Opus 5.5, best outputs ever.
And you'll notice that it also put a
little bit of an overlay under this text
because once again, I wanted to make
sure that we could actually read it. So,
very, very well done there. Then I said,
for the rest of the video, when I'm
talking about B-roll and screenshots and
generating images and videos, I want you
to have things come in on the left and
right side of the screen. Once again,
they should have some sort of overlay,
and I want you to actually go off and
get a B-roll screen recording and get a
screenshot and pull in stuff because I
want you to prove to the viewers that
you're able to do all of this. The whole
point is that I'm explaining what Opus
is capable of when it comes to animating
and editing videos, and I want you to
prove it in real time. Now, that is
basically my entire prompt. And what's
so cool about that is that it goes off
and it does it, but it also puts its own
spin on things. Like, you'll notice at
the very beginning, it's doing this very
subtle zoom in effect. I didn't ask for
that, but it just kind of knew to do
that to make it more engaging. I didn't
ask for this either when I said the one
prompt thing right there. It just did
that by itself with a super cool claw
looking interface. I didn't ask for this
either, but I absolutely love it. And
then you'll see what it interpreted when
I said get the screen recording, get the
screenshot, generate an image, generate
video. It did all of that on its own.
Amazing taste. The verification, I
thought this was a super clean animation
right here, the verification with like
screenshots and checking. You guys will
notice in my prompt, I didn't actually
ask for that at all. It just did it
because it thought that it would make
the intro more engaging. And I would
argue that it definitely did. And now
you can see that's all I said. I didn't
ask another prompt. And what we got was
that exact video right back here with
all of these things that we just saw.
Now, let's break down that other example
that you guys saw inside of the actual
intro itself. This little YouTube show
reel, which I was super, super impressed
by. This was also a oneshot prompt, like
I said. Really, really impressive.
There's so many things that wanted to
play here. It had to go get screenshots
of so many of my thumbnails, and then it
zoomed in on the thank you one, which I
think was amazing reasoning. It
literally said, "Okay, this is Nate
holding up the play button, saying thank
you. This is the one that we're going to
put in the center and this is the one
that we're going to zoom in on because I
think that highlights the branding and
the culture of YouTube which was just
insane. So anyways, it generated all of
this stuff and the sound and the music,
all of that. Right now, here's what I
did in this example. What's important is
that you're clear on what you want. And
you'll notice in the previous version, I
was like speaking very emotionally. And
that's what's cool about it is sometimes
you don't always know exactly what you
want, but you know the emotions you want
the video to create inside of you,
right? So what I did is I downloaded an
example that I saw on X. I saw this
example from Ken. Amazing output here
using hyperframes and using Opus. And
you'll notice there's a lot of
similarities with this reel and the one
that we just looked at with YouTube. So
basically what I did is I used this as
inspiration. I downloaded this video. I
then came into Claude Code and I gave it
to Claude Code and I said analyze this
video which was created by Opus 5.5 and
figure out why this is so good. So I
liked this video and I wanted to do
something similar. And I had Claude Code
figure out what that is. I had Opus
figure out why it's so good. And then I
said, "Turn that into a skill." So now
we have this skill called motion reel or
something. And I'm going to give that to
you guys for free. Just a sec. And then
I said, "Okay, use that skill. Create me
my own show reel about YouTube." I said,
"Collect B-roll images, any assets you
need. Make sure the whole thing feels
branded to YouTube. Typography, design,
language, colors, branding, all that
type of stuff that makes YouTube YouTube
should be unmistakable in the show
reel." And now we have our output. You
can see here it wrote this skill called
motion show reel. So, if I go into my
files real quick and I go to the skills
and we go all the way down to the M's,
we go to the motion show reel, we now
have this motion showre skill with all
of this information like about how we
actually design reels like this. So, I'm
going to put this inside of my um free
school community once again. So, if you
guys want it, hop into my free school
community and you can grab it in the
YouTube resources or inside of the AI
skills. It'll be in there. And now you
can do reels just like that. What you'll
also notice is that it had to go
generate these images. So you can see it
created these images and then it sent
them to cling in order to turn those
images into videos. And that's how we
actually got these animations inside of
the video right about here where we see
the actual play button sort of being
animated. These two scenes were because
it created an image and then it created
a video and then it sent it back to
Claude and then Opus took all that stuff
and put it into one consistent video.
Now, here's another showre style video,
but this one didn't use that skill that
we built at all. And just to show you
how cool stuff can be made, even without
a show reel. So, I said, "Make a dynamic
15-second motion graphics video that
shows what an incredible motion designer
you are, like it's your showre for a
resume. Go all out." I actually saw this
from someone on X. They made a demo, and
they said this is what they prompted it
with, so I tried it out. I said, "Make
it about our company, AIS. Use real
assets and logos from our products when
possible. You can also use key.ai AI to
generate any assets you need and use
hyperframes or any other tools for
motion design and music and sound
effects. And with one shot prompt, this
is what we got back right here. So,
let's take a look.
You can see the similarities at the
beginning with the little bead that like
drops and there's sound effects, but
then with the motion graphics, with the
color schemes, with the same sort of
like spatial awareness of doing things
like this, I thought was so cool. It
pulled pictures from our website. It
knew how many members we had. It had
this 3D sort of image which I think was
an image that was generated and then it
was turned into a video similar to that
YouTube show reel. Anyways, this
background image is from our website as
well. So, just very very well done. Real
quick guys, I've got this completely
free website design skill that I'm
giving away. I use this for every single
website that I build, including our AI
Automation Society site, which I think
is pretty slick, and I absolutely love
this website. It's called Scrollcraft
and it understands things like scroll
driven animations and layering, but also
it has things in there like taste,
typography, spacing, depth. It's just a
really good website design skill in
general and it's completely free. So,
the link for this will be down in the
description. But let's get back to the
video. Now, let me show you guys. This
is one of my like new favorite
benchmarks. I basically give Cloud Code
access to a folder which has 105 GB of
YouTube videos or sorry, not YouTube
videos, videos and recordings and
resources from our event AIS live. And
then I say, "Hey, look through all this
and create me a scissor reel. Tell a
story out of this." And look what I got
here. Now, this wasn't a oneshot prompt.
This was one prompt and then me giving
one round of iteration and then having
it fix one thing. So, technically three
prompts. That's why it is v2.1. But
let's take a look at this output right
here.
>> Hello. Hello. AIS live.
>> I'm so so pumped. It was electric.
>> Let's go.
>> Never even opened VS Code. Signed the
deal.
>> The chat's going crazy.
Drippy.
Fantastic event.
>> This was amazing.
>> Such a fun two days.
>> I literally like logged off yesterday
just buzzing. I had goosebumps.
>> Can't wait for the next one.
I mean, do you guys have any idea how
complicated that process is just to tell
a story out of an event when you just
are given a folder of resources? And of
course, it's marketing for our next one,
which is actually real coming up October
17th and 18th. So, mark your calendars
if you guys want to show up. More
details will be in the description. But
I know there were a few things that
weren't great. There were some times
where there was like an awkward cut of
the speech and a few things that we
could tweak, right? But look at this.
Look how it made like this tunnel of all
the screens. Look at the beginning how
it was zooming in on different screens.
Like it was really aware of the spacing.
And this is just really, really cool. It
was also pulling out specific moments in
the transcripts of these calls that were
showing kind of like the vibe and the
energy within the live event. This is my
favorite scene here at the end where it
has all of these scenes come together
and it forms the actual AIS live logo
even with the little red dot and then it
zooms in on the red dot and it says your
seat is in the middle. I just thought
that the way that it was able to
actually bring all of this to life is
really really impressive to me. Now I
also wanted to show you guys what else
is possible. Like a lot of times it's
about thinking of a use case. So I
recorded this really simple video of me
explaining how to make avocado toast and
I perfected that. By the way, my avocado
toast is so good. But anyways, I just
wanted to show you I did three different
edits with this avocado toast video.
This one I said, "Hey, I want you to
edit this using hyperframes. I'm looking
for a simple and clean whiteboard
handdrawn style animation." And it's
really simple as if you're trying to
explain to a kid how to make avat coast.
Simple graphics, simple animations, easy
to understand. If you need to generate
any images like or sorry assets like
images or videos, you can use key.ai. I
then said that some scenes should be a
full screen whiteboard takeover and some
scenes should just be the left half is
the whiteboard and the right half is my
face. So it then went ahead and started
generating things. It started reasoning.
It started testing things out and now we
have this output which I'll go ahead and
play right now. All right. So here's how
I make avocado toast. When you put the
toast in the toaster, when you're
letting it sit, you don't set it flat on
the plate because then that bottom side
gets a little soggy. You want that both
sides to be crispy. Then you put the
eggs on the pan. You mash up the
avocado. You spread the avocado on the
crispy bread. I put like everything
bagel seasoning on the avocado mash. And
then I do some balsamic vinegar. And
then you put the eggs on top of the
toast. And that's how it's done. Now, my
main critique here is that the eggs are
super tiny and the balsamic glaze is
only on one little piece of the toast.
So that wouldn't taste as good as if it
was everywhere. But anyways, look how
good this was able to in one prompt just
animate the stuff in a very simple and
engaging way. It's handdrawn. It is,
like I said, it's kind of friendly and
playful as if you wanted to show a kid.
But this was literally just one prompt
and it took care of everything. Now,
when I first really started using AI to
edit videos, it was for course style
videos, things that were super easy. We
just wanted them animated with like, you
know, bullet points and super simple
images and graphics. So, here's what I
did in this one. I need you to edit a
course style video for me using
hyperframes. My camera will start off
full screen and then I want it to be a
rounded crop. The background is going to
be super simple, super minimalistic. And
the style I'm looking for is just bullet
points with important takeaways, not too
wordy, and they should be big. And then
visual aids should just be AI generated
images, very simple, very light motion
graphics to help illustrate concepts.
And here is what we got. This was once
again a oneshot prompt. Oh, wait. That
was just an image. It was just doing
verification. Here we go. All right. So,
here's how I make avocado toast. When
you put the toast in the toaster, when
you're letting it sit, you don't set it
flat on the plate because then that
bottom side gets a little soggy. You
want that both sides to be crispy. Then
you put the eggs on the pan. You mash up
the avocado. You spread the avocado on
the crispy bread. I put like everything
bagel seasoning on the avocado mash. And
then I do some balsamic vinegar. And
then you put the eggs on top of the
toast. And that's how it's done. So all
of the images and videos in this video
were AI generated. All of this was AI
generated. And you can see that it's
going to save you so much time because
it can go get B-roll, it can take
screenshots, it can, you know, generate
things if you need it to. It's just
really cool because now you can film
content and editing doesn't have to be
the bottleneck anymore, especially when
you start to build skills around stuff
like your preferences and motion styles
and all that kind of stuff, your brand
guidelines. And then the last one I did
here was kind of a short form video and
this was using hyperframes once again.
And you'll notice that I'm not really
having this leverage other skills. So, I
wanted to show you how easy it is to do
a oneshot prompts with Obus 5.5. Pretty
much all these examples I've been
running on high, by the way. High
meaning the effort level. And I just
said basically this. Generate the assets
you need. Have it be engaging. Have it
be fast-paced, easy to understand. So,
let's see what we got down here for this
short. Here's how I make avocado toast.
When you put the toast in the toaster,
when you're letting it sit, you don't
set it flat on the plate because then
that bottom side gets a little soggy.
You want that both sides to be crispy.
Then you put the eggs on the pan. You
mash up the avocado. You spread the
avocado on the crispy bread. I put like
everything bagel seasoning on the
avocado mash and then I do some balsamic
vinegar and then you put the eggs on top
of the toast and that's how it's done.
I mean, it's not perfect, right? But a
oneshot prompt and it's just it's really
cool that it's able to switch between
these different scenes. It definitely
keeps my attention because we have all
the different sorts of B-roll going on
in the background. It is just a really
really decent output when you consider
what this would have taken for a human
to do it for you. And now oneshot
prompt. You iterate, you iterate, you
build skills. And I wanted to show you
guys one more example with Lululemon
because this is like a physical tangible
product. Look how good it did at making
this video feel like Lululemon.
So, if you guys think about what it
actually had to do there, all of these
videos were obviously AI generated, but
what I'm pretty sure it did is it went
to Lululemon and it found all these
actual pieces of clothing. It found
them. It took pictures of the actual
model here and then generated videos of
them running or jumping or whatever it
is in the clothes and then of course it
brings it all together here with actual
catalog images. It's just really cool to
think about how many little pieces would
have had to go into this if you were
editing this or creating this as a
human. But really as a human all I did
was I told it what I wanted and sort of
the emotional feeling I wanted it to
carry throughout the vibe. high energy,
fast-paced, engaging, sync the music to
the beats, sound effects, things like
that. So, I just wanted to talk about
the five things that I'm constantly
thinking about when I'm actually editing
videos with AI. I'm just going to run
through these super simply because you
just you could basically give the
transcript of this section to your AI
agent and it would be fine. So, the
first piece is to transcribe. If you're
starting off with a clip and you need it
to be edited, like you know, a video or
a course or whatever it is, you
obviously want to transcribe first so
that the beats can come in at the right
time and so that the AI knows how to
tell a story out of it. Transcribe is
essential. Whether you want to use
Whisper or 11 Labs or some other tool,
transcribing is essential. From there,
you're going to have it cut things out.
So, if it's mistakes, cut out the
mistakes. If it notices in the
transcript that there's like 20 seconds
of dead space, cut out the dead space.
Things like that. You're cutting things
up. And a lot of times I'll use AI just
to literally cut out mistakes and then
I'll take the clip and do whatever I
want with it. But it's able to just
clean out your content so much quicker
than you could because you'd be in the
the editor looking for the dead space
and then you know snipping everything
out. And then number three is to plan
the beats. A lot of times from there
what I like to do is I like to be very
specific about what it is that I want.
As you guys saw in this intro version,
the intro for this video, I was
basically just planning out what I
wanted. Now, obviously, it went off the
cuff a little bit and it was creative,
but if I would have said like, "These
are the only beats I want you to
actually create." Nothing else, it would
have done that. But I let it be creative
here. But I basically said, "Hey, at
this point, I want this to come in. I
want this to come in. I want this to
come in." And the better you can set
expectations of what you're looking for
and what you would consider good,
obviously, the better, or not better,
but the more aligned your output is
going to be. Number four is to use
skills. So, build skills around things.
If you build a lot of reels, then build
skills around reels. Use my Hyperframe
student kit. use resources and use
inspiration like you guys saw me do. I
took a video that I really liked and I
told it to build a skill. Now, guess
what? Every time I run that skill, I
will look at the output and say, "Hey,
in this version, I really liked this and
I really didn't like this." Update the
skill with that information, run it
again, and then I'll give you more
feedback. And that way, you're actually
building a reusable component where
every single time you run the skill,
it's getting better, and you're able to
just move faster and faster. You don't
want to have to repeat yourself every
time. If you ever find yourself
repeating something, just throw it in
the skill. And then the fifth one,
probably the most important one, is the
verification loop. You'll notice how as
it's going through a lot of my videos,
it's taking screenshots and looking at
them and then making iterations. And
that's how you get in that loop where
you're not just basically saying, "Okay,
here is my output number one." You're
getting output number like five or six
because the agent basically did this. It
delivered output one and then it watched
it. It realized there was some mistakes
and then it came back and it delivered
output two and then it watched output
two and then it kept iterating on its
outputs until it realized okay this one
is finally good enough where I'm going
to give it to Nate and here you go Nate
this is the finished video. So now
you're getting something that has
already been checked by the AI and
iterated on then you know compared to if
it just handed you this first version
and then you're frustrated and you have
to make all these you know prompts. But
anyways guys, there are so many use
cases when it comes to using AI to help
you edit things or add motion design
because it's not really something that
you had to have previous video editing
experience in order to take advantage of
now. So don't let editing be your
bottleneck. But that's going to do it
for today. If you enjoyed, you learned
something new, please give a like. It
helps me out a ton. And as always, I
appreciate you guys making it to the end
of the video. I'll see you on the next
one. Thanks everyone.